 const questions = [

{
        "numb": 151,
        "question": "Most potent stimulator of naive T cell is: ",
        "answer": "Dendritic cell ",
        "options": [
            "Plasma cell ",
            "NA",
            "Dendritic cell ",
            "B cell",
            "Macrophages "
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 152,
        "question": "A 32-year-old male presents with recurrent episodes of abdominal pain, diarrhea, and bloody stools. Colonoscopy reveals areas of inflammation and ulceration in the colon. What inflammatory bowel disease is he likely suffering from?",
        "answer": "Ulcerative colitis",
        "options": [
            "Diverticulitis",
            "Celiac disease",
            "Irritable bowel syndrome (IBS)",
            "Crohn's disease",
            "Ulcerative colitis"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 153,
        "question": "Which autoimmune disorder is associated with elevated levels of antinuclear antibodies and decreased complement levels?",
        "answer": "Systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE)",
        "options": [
            "Systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE)",
            "Type 1 diabetes mellitus",
            "Multiple sclerosis",
            "Crohn's disease",
            "Rheumatoid arthritis"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 154,
        "question": "Oxygen burst I Respiratory burst is the ra pid release of reactive oxygen species , superoxide anions and hydrogen peroxide from different cell types. Plays a vital role in cell signalling. Which of the following helps in generat ing oxygen burst in the neutrophils? ",
        "answer": "NADPH oxidase",
        "options": [
            "NA",
            "Glutathione peroxidase ",
            "Catalase ",
            "Superoxide dismutase",
            "NADPH oxidase"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 155,
        "question": "Which mechanism of immune response is characterized by specific recognition and attack of pathogens?\n",
        "answer": " Cellular immunity",
        "options": [
            "Inflammation\n\n",
            " Antibodies\n ",
            " Phagocytosis\n",
            " Cellular immunity",
            "Apoptosis\n"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 156,
        "question": "Which of the following molecules is the major signaling protein that activates immune cells and is involved in the inflammatory response?\n\n",
        "answer": " Tumor Necrosis Factor (TNF)",
        "options": [
            " Tumor Necrosis Factor (TNF)",
            "Transforming Growth Factor Beta (TGF-?)",
            "Interleukin-2",
            "Interferon gamma",
            " Interferon"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 157,
        "question": "Which of the following mechanisms is associated with the development of allergic reactions?",
        "answer": "Sensitization of mast cells",
        "options": [
            "Increased production of IgG antibodies",
            "Desensitization of mast cells",
            "Sensitization of mast cells",
            "Activation of regulatory T cells",
            "Suppression of cytokine release"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 158,
        "question": "A 35-year-old woman presents with recurrent hives and swelling of the lips and face after eating certain foods. She has noticed these symptoms after consuming shellfish, nuts, and strawberries. Skin prick testing reveals sensitization to multiple food allergens. What dietary modification could help prevent future allergic reactions?",
        "answer": "Elimination of identified food allergens",
        "options": [
            "Incorporating probiotics into the diet",
            "Increasing intake of allergenic foods",
            "Avoidance of fruits and vegetables",
            "Fasting for extended periods",
            "Elimination of identified food allergens"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 159,
        "question": "During a Type 1 hypersensitive reaction, the binding of allergens to IgE antibodies on mast cells triggers the release of:",
        "answer": "Histamine",
        "options": [
            "Antibodies",
            "Interleukins",
            "Interferons",
            "Histamine",
            "Complement proteins"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 160,
        "question": "Which of the following best describes the mechanism of Type 2 Hypersensitivity?",
        "answer": "Antibody-dependent cell-mediated cytotoxicity",
        "options": [
            "Local immune complex injury",
            "Immune complex deposition",
            "Delayed-type hypersensitivity",
            "Antibody-dependent cell-mediated cytotoxicity",
            "Immune response to soluble antigens in the blood"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 161,
        "question": "A 20-year-old gardener presents to his family physician with his hands and arms appearing red, covered with oozing blisters and crusts. Which of the following best describes the pathogenesis of these skin lesions? ",
        "answer": "Delayed-type hypersensitivity",
        "options": [
            "Deposition of circulating immune complexes",
            "Delayed-type hypersensitivity",
            "NA",
            "Deposition of antigluten antibodies ",
            "Cytotoxic antibody production "
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 162,
        "question": "Hyperacute rejection is due to",
        "answer": "Preformed antibodies",
        "options": [
            "Preformed antibodies",
            "Endothelitis caused by donor antibodies",
            "Circulating macrophage- mediated injury",
            "NA",
            "Cytotoxic T lymphocyte-mediated injury "
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 163,
        "question": "Method of prevention of GVHD in bone marrow transplantation is: ",
        "answer": "AlI are correct",
        "options": [
            "NA",
            "Post procedure immune suppression",
            "Prior immune suppression ",
            "T-cell removal",
            "AlI are correct"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 164,
        "question": "Which primary immunodeficiency disorder is characterized by selective deficiency of immunoglobulin A (IgA), leading to recurrent respiratory and gastrointestinal infections?",
        "answer": "Selective IgA deficiency",
        "options": [
            "Chronic granulomatous disease",
            "X-linked agammaglobulinemia",
            "Common variable immunodeficiency",
            "Selective IgA deficiency",
            "Severe combined immunodeficiency"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 165,
        "question": "A 12-year-old girl presents with recurrent skin abscesses and lymphadenopathy. Laboratory tests show impaired phagocytosis by neutrophils. What primary immunodeficiency disorder is she likely suffering from?",
        "answer": "Chronic granulomatous disease",
        "options": [
            "Severe combined immunodeficiency",
            "Selective IgA deficiency",
            "X-linked agammaglobulinemia",
            "Chronic granulomatous disease",
            "Common variable immunodeficiency"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 166,
        "question": "Risk of HIV transmission is not seen with: ",
        "answer": "Plasma derived Hepatitis B vaccine ",
        "options": [
            "Platelets ",
            "Leucocytes",
            "Whole blood ",
            "NA",
            "Plasma derived Hepatitis B vaccine "
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 167,
        "question": "A 28-year-old woman presents with fever, weight loss, and generalized lymphadenopathy. She reports unprotected sexual intercourse with multiple partners. On examination, she has oral hairy leukoplakia and Pneumocystis jirovecii pneumonia. What is the most likely diagnosis?",
        "answer": "Secondary immunodeficiency",
        "options": [
            "Chronic granulomatous disease",
            "Sarcoidosis",
            "Hypersensitivity reaction",
            "Secondary immunodeficiency",
            "Primary immunodeficiency"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 168,
        "question": "Which of the following is a systemic sign of severe inflammation characterized by decreased blood pressure and organ dysfunction? ",
        "answer": "Sepsis",
        "options": [
            "Hyperemia",
            "Sepsis",
            "Leukocytosis",
            "Anaphylaxis",
            "Erythema"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 169,
        "question": "What is the term for the process by which neutrophils squeeze through endothelial gaps to migrate to the site of injury or infection?",
        "answer": " Diapedesis ",
        "options": [
            "Margination ",
            " Diapedesis ",
            " Exocytosis",
            " Chemotaxis ",
            " Phagocytosis "
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 170,
        "question": "A 60-year-old obese male presents with severe pain, redness, and swelling in his left big toe. He reports a history of consuming a high-purine diet and excessive alcohol intake. Laboratory investigations reveal elevated serum uric acid levels. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?",
        "answer": " Ankylosing spondylitis",
        "options": [
            " Ankylosing spondylitis",
            "Osteoarthritis",
            " Rheumatoid arthritis",
            " Septic arthritis",
            " Gouty arthritis"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 171,
        "question": "An anti-inflammatory cytokine is ",
        "answer": "IL-4",
        "options": [
            "IL-1",
            "TNF",
            "IFNy",
            "IL-4",
            "NA"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 172,
        "question": "A 33 year old male presents with complaints of Itching and generalised redness who developed erythematous pruritic lesions all over the body which was triggered after washing his clothes. Which statement is not true in this case?",
        "answer": "Histamine receptor agonists are used to treat allergies.",
        "options": [
            "NA",
            "Histamine is a principal mediator of immediate transient response during acute inflammation.",
            "It increases the permeability of venules ",
            "It causes dilation of arterioles ",
            "Histamine receptor agonists are used to treat allergies."
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 173,
        "question": "What is the name of the inflammation, characterized by the outpouring of low-protein fluid?",
        "answer": "Serous inflammation",
        "options": [
            "Catarrhal inflammation",
            "Purulent inflammation",
            "Fibrinous inflammation",
            "Serous inflammation",
            "Hemorrhagic inflammation"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 174,
        "question": "Cell to cell permeability occurs through:",
        "answer": "Connexins",
        "options": [
            "Occludin",
            "NA",
            "Zona adherens",
            "Connexins",
            "Zonulin"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 175,
        "question": "Which of these is not a granulomatous disease",
        "answer": "Amebiasis",
        "options": [
            "Amebiasis",
            "Sarcoidosis",
            "Leprosy",
            "Tuberculosis",
            "Neutrophil infiltration"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 176,
        "question": "Chronic granulomatous disease is:",
        "answer": "Associated with formation of multiple granulomas",
        "options": [
            "Margination",
            "A benign neoplastic process",
            "Associated with formation of multiple granulomas",
            "A parasitic disease",
            "Acquired leukocyte function defect"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 177,
        "question": "Prostaglandin causing fever is: ",
        "answer": "PGE2 ",
        "options": [
            "PGE1",
            "PGF2 ",
            "PGE2 ",
            "PGT2",
            "NA"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 178,
        "question": "A 55-year-old male with a history of rheumatoid arthritis presents with recurrent episodes of fever, joint pain, and fatigue. He is currently on immunosuppressive therapy. Laboratory tests reveal elevated levels of inflammatory markers. What is the likely explanation for his recurrent fevers?",
        "answer": "Endogenous pyrogen release due to his autoimmune condition",
        "options": [
            "Endogenous pyrogen release due to his autoimmune condition",
            "Hypothalamic dysfunction caused by long-term immunosuppressive therapy",
            "Exogenous pyrogens produced by an underlying infection",
            "Fever of unknown origin",
            "Side effect of his medication"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 179,
        "question": "Which type of viral genome integrates into the host cell's DNA and remains latent, occasionally reactivating to produce new virions?",
        "answer": "Retrovirus",
        "options": [
            "Single-stranded DNA ",
            "Retrovirus",
            "Double-stranded RNA ",
            "Single-stranded RNA",
            "Double-stranded DNA "
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 180,
        "question": "In viral replication, which enzyme is responsible for synthesizing a complementary RNA strand from a viral RNA template?",
        "answer": "RNA-dependent RNA polymerase",
        "options": [
            "RNA-dependent RNA polymerase",
            "Reverse transcriptase ",
            "RNAase ",
            "DNA polymerase ",
            "DNA ligase"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 181,
        "question": "Definition of Metaplasia is",
        "answer": "Columnar is the most common type",
        "options": [
            "Columnar is the most common type",
            "NA",
            "Is irreversible",
            "Involves only epithelial cells",
            "Can occurs at stem cells level"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 182,
        "question": "A 56 Yr old Female complaints of heavy menstrual bleeding for the past 1 month,associated with pain. She added that her last menstruation was 10 years back. On Per Vaginalexamination, Non-Bloody vaginal discharge noted & patient was irritable and anxious during examination. Endometrial !biopsy was taken in OPD which revealed atypical cells. Which pathological process we will not find in this case?",
        "answer": "Bone marrow hyperplasia is not seen in response to peripheral blood cytopenias",
        "options": [
            "There is an increase in the number of cells",
            "NA",
            "Pathological hyperplasia can be a risk factor for malignancy ",
            "Bone marrow hyperplasia is not seen in response to peripheral blood cytopenias",
            "Seen in cells capable of dividing (labile cells)"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 183,
        "question": "Which organs lack stable cells?",
        "answer": "Skeletal muscle",
        "options": [
            "Liver",
            "Pancreas",
            "Smooth muscle",
            "Skeletal muscle",
            "NA"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 184,
        "question": " The patient consulted a surgeon at the clinic with a wound in the area of the right shoulder joint. The bottom of the wound upon examination has a fine-grained surface of a red-pink color. Which of the following types of regeneration develops in this case?",
        "answer": "Incomplete reparative regeneration",
        "options": [
            "physiological regeneration",
            "Incomplete reparative regeneration",
            "humoral regeneration",
            "pathological regeneration",
            "complete reparative regeneration"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 185,
        "question": "Which of the following is not a sign of a malignancy",
        "answer": "Sensitivity to growth-inhibitory signals",
        "options": [
            "Evasion of apoptosis",
            "Sustained angiogenesis",
            "Self-sufficiency in growth signals",
            "NA",
            "Sensitivity to growth-inhibitory signals"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 186,
        "question": "A 68 yr old woman with a repeated bouts of pneumonia and H/O heavy smoking presents with a 2-week history of fever and productive cough. A chest X-ray reveals a right lower lobe infiltrates confirming pneumonia. A transbronchial biopsy was done revealing preneoplastic changes within the bronchial mucosa. Which of the following best characterizes the morphology of this bronchial mucosa lesion?",
        "answer": "Cellular maturation shows abnormal pattern ",
        "options": [
            "NA",
            "Invasiveness ",
            "presence of poorly diiferentiated keratin producing cells",
            "Increased numbers of otherwise normal cells ",
            "Cellular maturation shows abnormal pattern "
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 187,
        "question": " Classification of neoplasms by WHO is based on",
        "answer": "Histogenesis of tumors.",
        "options": [
            ".Localization of tumors.",
            "Morphogenesis of tumors",
            "Etiology of tumors",
            "Differentiation of tumors",
            "Histogenesis of tumors."
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 188,
        "question": "Growth of tumor into the lumen of hollow organ is called",
        "answer": "Exophytic",
        "options": [
            "Invasive",
            "Endophytic",
            "Unicentric",
            "Expansive",
            "Exophytic"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 189,
        "question": "Where is localized squamous cell papilloma?",
        "answer": "Vagina",
        "options": [
            "Ureter",
            "Urethra",
            "Calyces of kidney",
            "Vagina",
            "Pelvis of kidney "
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 190,
        "question": "A 45-year-old woman presents with complaints of post-coital bleeding. She is diagnosed to have invasive carcinoma of the cervix. Which of the following features differentiate invasive carcinoma from dysplasia or carcinoma in situ?",
        "answer": "Invasion of the basement membrane",
        "options": [
            "Typical mitoses",
            "Pleomorphism",
            "NA",
            "Nuclear hyperchromasia",
            "Invasion of the basement membrane"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 191,
        "question": "Overgrowth of a bile duct at localized region is?",
        "answer": "Hamartoma",
        "options": [
            "Hamartoma",
            "Choriostoma",
            "Malignant tumor",
            "NA",
            "Polyp"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 192,
        "question": "A woman of Asian ethnicity has a 0.5x0.3 cm dark node, elevated above the skin, with a smooth surface. Microscopic examination shows dendritic cells with high melanin content. Which type of tumor occurs in this case?",
        "answer": "Blue nevus",
        "options": [
            "Hemangioma",
            " Dysplastic nevi",
            "Hybernoma",
            "Blue nevus",
            "Lentigo"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 193,
        "question": "Commonest type of pigmented nevus is",
        "answer": "Compound nevus",
        "options": [
            "Juvenile nevus.",
            "Junctional nevus.",
            "Blue nevus",
            "Compound nevus",
            "Intradermal nevus"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 194,
        "question": "A 46-year-old man has a dark spot on his skin, which began to grow larger and pain appeared. Microscopically: Tumor cells have amphophilic cytoplasm and large pleomorphic nuclei with prominent nucleoli. What type of tumor is there in this case?",
        "answer": "Melanoma",
        "options": [
            " Blue nevus",
            "Melanoma",
            "Lentigo",
            "Hemangioma",
            "Dysplastic nevi"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 195,
        "question": "If catabolism is more than anabolism what would it be means?",
        "answer": "negative nitrogen  balance",
        "options": [
            "increased stabilized protein synthesis",
            "negative nitrogen  balance",
            "increased growth protein synthesis",
            "protein breakdown not change",
            "positive nitrogen balance"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 196,
        "question": "Which one of following changes in blood, related to protein metabolism disorders, is commonly risk factor for formation of stones in urinary tract?  ",
        "answer": "hyperuricemia ",
        "options": [
            "paraproteinemia",
            "azotemia",
            "hyperuricemia ",
            "uremia",
            "dysproteinemia"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 197,
        "question": "What is the main pathophysiological process underlying the development of atherosclerosis?",
        "answer": "Chronic inflammation in blood vessels",
        "options": [
            "Decreased levels of low-density lipoprotein (LDL) cholesterol",
            "",
            "Excessive intake of dietary fiber",
            "Chronic inflammation in blood vessels",
            "Enhanced endothelial function"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 198,
        "question": "Concerning lipid metabolism, chylomicrons absorption is damaged through which one of these?",
        "answer": "lacteal of villi ",
        "options": [
            "lacteal of villi ",
            "blood capillary",
            "lymph capillary",
            "brush border of enterocytes",
            "bile capillary"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 199,
        "question": "Which of the following statements is true for type 1 diabetes?",
        "answer": "It is an autoimmune disease",
        "options": [
            "It is insulin dependent diabetes",
            "It is an autoimmune disease",
            "NA",
            "It is not associated with thyroid disorders",
            "Insulin resistance is the hallmark of the disease pathogenesis"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 200,
        "question": "Which of the following is not a test for diabetes mellitus?",
        "answer": "D-Xylose test",
        "options": [
            "D-Xylose test",
            "NA",
            "Fructossamine assay",
            "Fasting blood sugar",
            "Random blood sugar"
        ]
    }
];